# SAM KAMALI







### Introduction

My academic foundation includes a Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering and an Interactive Media Design diploma. I stand out as a fusion of technical expertise and creative ingenuity. Web app design and development are my professional passions, and I excel in the dynamic tech landscape, where adaptability and rapid learning are second nature to me.

# Professional Experience

**April 2023 - Aug 2023** litto

### UI/UX Designer (Internship)

- Designed Figma wireframes to improve post-sign-up pages.
- Enhanced main and option pages with essential features and intuitive options.
- Streamlined user journey, improving overall platform functionality.

### **Karbord Computer Software**

Senior Front-end Developer (Full-time, Remote) Jan 2022 - May 2022

- Transformed client portal with ReactJS and SASS, boosting user experience and enhancing functionality.
- Integrated external APIs and third-party libraries for enhanced functionality in React applications.

Senior UI/UX Designer (Full-time, Remote) Jun 2021 - Nov 2021

Led UI/UX for client application, prioritizing user-centric design Figma.

Yekta Rose Dec 2020 - June 2021

### Web Designer and Content Analyst (Full-time)

- Collaborated within a dynamic development team to create responsive and user-friendly web applications using React.js.
- Engaged in cross-functional teamwork to develop integrated solutions for WordPress platforms.
- Worked closely with SEO, SEM and Ecommerce teams to leverage best web experiences.

### **IranKhodro Khorasan Car Manufacturing** June 2020 - Nov 2020

IT Specialist (Full-time)

Implemented SAP and SEO solutions that resulted in improved efficiency, cost savings, and increased online visibility.

### **Shabih Film-Making Studio**

Sep 2019 - Mar 2020

### Video Editor/Content Creator (Full-time)

- Contributed to a versatile team handling video editing, Instagram layout design, and content creation.
- Created short and long video ads for the "Mazzeh" cooking show.

## Software Skills

### Web Development and Programming:

HTML, JavaScript, ReactJs, VueJs, CSS, SASS, tailwind, PHP, C++, Python, WordPress, Shopify, Drupal

### **Design and Multimedia:**

Adobe [ Illustrator, Photoshop, XD, InDesign, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Lightroom, Audition ], Figma, Canva

### **Data Management and Analytics:**

SEO, SEM, MySQL, Firebase, Google Analytics, Google Ads

### **IT and Cybersecurity:**

Microsoft [Word, Excel, Access, Azure, Visio, Sharepoint],

Linux, IT fundamentals, RestAPI, MATLAB, Machine learning fundamentals

# **Education**

### Algonquin College (Ottawa)

Diploma - Interactive Media Design CGPA: (3.9/4)

Dean's Honors List

### Azad University (Iran)

Bachelor's Degree Computer Engineering, IT CGPA: (3.6/4)